Finding Aid for Huron River Watershed Council Records, 1965-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Huron River Watershed Council Records 1965-2013
Huron River Watershed Council.
0528 Bn 2
Council was established in 1965 to promote and coordinate studies and plans regarding the water resources of the Huron River watershed. Executive committee files including minutes and agendas, reports and correspondence; also annual reports and financial statements, and newsletters and published research studies and reports.
6 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of the Council (donor no. 4971 ) and came to the library in March 2004. Periodic additions have been received.
The record group is open to research.
On March 5, 1965, a petition was filed with the Michigan Water Resources Commission for the establishment of a Huron River Watershed Council. The petition was filed by local governmental units lying within the Huron River watershed in Washtenaw, Livingston, Oakland, Wayne, and Monroe counties. The purpose of the Council was to promote and coordinate studies and plans regarding the water resources of the watershed and to keep the public informed on issues and conditions through reports and recommendations. With its accumulated knowledge and the perspective which its membership could provide about the watershed, the Council intended to be a review and advisory agency to the river management district and to various federal and state agencies. The Council replaced the Huron River Watershed Intergovernmental Committee which had been established in 1958.
The record group includes files of the executive committee consisting of minutes and agenda, reports, correspondence, and other materials relating to the activities of the Council. There are also annual reports, financial statements, newsletters, miscellaneous research studies and reports, and videotapes on water resource topics.
Subjects:
Huron River Watershed Council.; Huron River Watershed (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Water-supply--Michigan, Southeastern.; Water conservation--Michigan, Southeastern.
- Executive Committee files
  (includes agendas, minutes, reports, etc.)
  - 1965-1967 (Box 1)
    (documenting the formation of the Council)
  - 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1982 (Box 1)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - January 2002-March 2006, 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 4)
- Reports
  - Annual Reports 1982-2004 (Box 1)
    (published reports; mimeographed reports scattered throughout Executive Committee files)
  - Staff Reports 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Financial Reports/Financial Statements 1984-2002 (Box 2)
- By-laws
  - May 5, 1965 (Box 2)
    (third draft)
  - June 1968 (Box 2)
    (revision 1999)
- Publications
  - Calendars 2003, 2006, 2008, 2010, 2012-2013 (Box 2)
  - Educational pamphlets and mailings 2000s (Box 2)
  - Newsletters 1966-2013 (scattered), 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Research studies and reports 1965-2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Research studies and reports 2001-2007, 2 folders (Box 6)
- Reports
  - 319 Nonpoint Source Implementation Project, Years 5 and 6 Report Implementing an Education Strategy for the Huron River Watershed (Box 6)
  - I/E Campaign Annual Reports (Box 6)
  - Watershed Planning for TMDL's, A Step by Step Workbook (Box 6)
- Management Plans
  - The Brighton Lake Subwatershed Management Plan: A strategy to meet the total maximum daily load for Brighton Lake 2002, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - The Kent Lake Subwatershed Management Plan: A strategy to meet the total maximum daily load for Kent Lake 2002, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Mill Creek Subwatershed Management Plan 2003, 1 volumes (Box 3)
    (include CD)
  - Lower Huron River Subwatershed Management Plan 2005, 2 volumes (Box 3)
- Reading File: outgoing correspondence, reports, press releases
  - 1981-1989, 6 volumes (Box 4)
    (lacking volume for 1982-1983)
- Topical File and Miscellaneous
  - Ann Arbor Huron River Committee 1985-1988 (Box 4)
  - Creek sheds project 1974 (Box 4)
  - Groundwater Pollution, HRWC Report on 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Huron River Day (Box 4)
  - Huron River history (collected materials) (Box 4)
  - Michigan Association of Watershed Organizations 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Position papers; reports (Box 4)
  - Upper Huron River Preservation Group 1985 (Box 4)
  - HRWC Ad campaign, CD (Box 4)
- Visual material
  - By date
    - 4th Annual Growing Community, Quality Through Design 1997 (Box 5)
    - Randall Arendt Workshop February 15, 2000, 2 tapes (Box 5)
    - The Natural History Mystery 2001 (Box 5)
    - Farming & Farmland Protection in Washtenaw County February 8, 2003 (Box 5)
      (tape 1)
    - Farming & Farmland Protection in Washtenaw County (Box 5)
      (tape 2)
  - By title undated
    - Grand Traverse Bay Region, Development Guidebook (Box 5)
    - Growth Management: A Question of Balance (Box 5)
    - Michigan Forum (Box 5)
  - Millers Creec Film festival 2006-2010, 8 optical disks DVDs